Guide to the Full Frame Archive Collection, 1998-2017 RL.00424
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2007
  - For the Bible Tells Me So (2007)
    This film illuminates the mercurial nature of biblical interpretations and the diverse philosophies of homosexuality they engender, illustrating the heated battles over homosexuality within Christian America through personal stories. Five Christian families who have come to terms with a gay or lesbian child are profiled; they discuss honestly how they coped with the tensions between religious beliefs, cultural expectations, and their love for their families. The solutions they find are as varied as the families themselves. The families of Congressman Richard Gephardt and Bishop Gene Robinson are among those profiled. Their stories are contextualized within the broader theological debate, including contributions from Anita Bryant, Rev. Jimmy Creech, Dr. James Dobson, Rev. Peter Gomes, Rabbi Steve Greenberg, Dr. Laurence C. Keene, Andrew Sullivan, and Bishop Desmond Tutu. Ultimately, the film offers pathways to family healing and understanding in the face of hatred.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 95)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 96)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 97)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 98)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 99)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 6 of 6, 1455 ft. (Reel 100)
    - DVD master, TRT 97:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Festival materials, 2007
    - Programs, pamphlets, postcards, 2007 (Box 6, Box 16)
    - T-shirts, tote bags, 2007; 2 shirts; 2 bags (Box 16)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2008
  - Man On Wire (2007)
    Director: James Marsh
    Producers: Simon Chinn
    On August 7, 1974, Philippe Petit, a young French wire walker and street performer, stepped out onto a wire illegally rigged between the Twin Towers of New York's World Trade Center. He spent nearly an hour walking, dancing, kneeling, and lying on the wire 1,350 feet above the streets of Manhattan before being arrested. After six years of dreaming and planning, Petit and a team of friends smuggled cables and equipment past security and rig them to withstand wind and swaying, all without being detected. Evoking a heist film, Man on Wire uses rare historic footage and stills along with re-enactments and present-day interviews with co-conspirators to tell the story of "the artistic crime of the century."
    In English and French with English subtitles
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 84)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 85)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 86)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 87)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 88)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 6 of 6, 1350 ft. (Reel 89)
    - DVD master, TRT 90:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Trouble the Water (2007)
    Directors: Carl Deal and Tia Lessin
    Producers: Carl Deal and Tia Lessin
    Awards won: Anne Dellinger Grand Jury Award; Full Frame/Working Films Award; and The Kathleen Bryan Edwards Award for Human Rights
    A street-level account of Hurricane Katrina (2005), the film opens the day before the storm with footage by aspiring rap artist Kimberly Rivers Roberts of her Ninth Ward neighborhood. With no way to leave the city, she and her husband Scott tape their harrowing ordeal as the floodwaters rise. This 15 minutes of home movie footage is interwoven with archival news segments and verité footage shot over the next two years, telling a story of remarkable people surviving not only failed levees, bungling bureaucrats and armed soldiers, but also their own past.
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 41)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 42)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 43)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 44)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 45)
    - DVD master, TRT 94:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - City of Cranes (2007)
    Producer: Samantha Sarzoza
    TRT: 14:00
    City of Cranes takes the viewer on a journey high up into the sky to experience the world of London's crane drivers, working hundreds of feet above the ground, only surrounded by a small metal cage. The film is divided into four chapters, each on a different aspect of a driver's life, from their unique contribution to a changing London to their relationship with the machines they operate, to the mental and physical challenges their job poses, to the impact of their solitary existence in their lives.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 14:00 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 14:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Lioness (2008)
    Directors: Meg McLagan and Daria Sommers
    Producers: Meg McLagan and Daria Sommers
    TRT: 83:00
    Lioness tells the story of five female Army soldiers who were among the first women in U.S. history to be sent into direct ground combat. Without the same training as their male counterparts but committed to serve as needed, they fought in some of the bloodiest battles of the second Iraq war, becoming part of the first generation of female combat veterans. Told through intimate accounts, journal excerpts, archival footage, and interviews with military commanders, the film forms a portrait of the emotional and psychological effects of war from a female point of view.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 83:00 (Box 3)
    - DVD master, TRT 83:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - In a Dream (2008)
    Director: Jeremiah Zagar
    Producer: Jeremy Yaches
    Over the past four decades, Isaiah Zagar has covered more than 50,000 square feet of Philadelphia with stunning mosaic murals. His son Jeremiah chronicles his father's work and tumultuous relationship with his wife, Julia, following them as their marriage implodes. The film is a beautiful and unsettling look into what it can mean to be an artist, walking the edge of sanity, and to be part of an artist's family.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 78:00 (Box 5)
    - Preservation tape master, HDCAM, TRT 78:00 (Box 5)
    - DVD master, TRT 78:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Taking Root: The Vision of Wangari Maathai (2008)
    Directors: Alan Dater and Lisa Merton
    Producers: Alan Dater and Lisa Merton
    Award won: Full Frame Women in Leadership Award
    Nobel Peace Prize Laureate Wangari Maathai transformed the simple act of planting trees into Kenya's Green Belt Movement, a nationwide political movement to safeguard the environment, protect human rights, and defend democracy, as Kenya recovered, politically, culturally and environmentally from colonial exploitation. In the past thirty years, this charismatic woman has emerged as an icon of pro-democracy activism and feminism.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 80:00 (Box 5)
    - DVD master, TRT 80:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - At the Death House Door (2008)
    Directors: Steve James and Peter Gilbert
    Producers: Steve James and Peter Gilbert
    Awards won: Full Frame Inspiration Award
    For 15 years, Carroll Pickett, minister to death row inmates at a penitentiary in Texas, had no reservations about presiding over executions, until his path crossed that of Carlos de Luna, unjustly accused of homicide. Pickett became unshakably convinced of the man's innocence, and teamed up with crime reporters from the Chicago Tribune to delve into the facts surrounding De Luna's arraignment. This documentary uses Pickett's story as a springboard into broader issues about capital punishment.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 96:00 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 96:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Summerchild (2007)
    Directors: Iris Olsson
    Producer: Kai Kuikkaniemi
    Country: Finland
    Awards won: Full Frame President's Award
    Over the summer vacation, a Finnish couple opens their home to a Russian orphan who lives in an orphanage just over the border; the distance between them turns out to be much greater. Eleven-year-old Sveta speaks no Finnish and struggles to express herself; the well-meaning Finns, Tiina and Peter, attempt to communicate through bedtime stories and shopping sprees. But are good intentions enough to acclimatize Sveta to the west and bridge the gap? Can an act of charity become a real connection?
    In Finnish and Russian with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 60:00 (Box 2)
    - DVD master, TRT 60:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Please Vote For Me (2007)
    Director: Weijun Chen
    Producer: Don Edkins
    Country: China / Denmark
    TRT: 55:00
    This film documents an experiment in democracy and electoral politics in a third-grade classroom in Wuhan, a major city in central China. For the first time, the students elect their own class monitor, who would normally be appointed by the teacher. Chen's film follows the dramatic two-week campaign, from the introduction of the candidates to the final vote. Please Vote For Me is a thought-provoking look at how these Chinese children, parents and teachers understand democracy, authority, and power.
    In Chinese with English subtitles
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 3, 1650 ft. (Reel 47)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 3, 1650 ft. (Reel 48)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 3, 1650 ft. (Reel 49)
    - DVD master, TRT 55:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - The Betrayal (Nerakhoon) (2008)
    Directors: Ellen Kuras and Thavisouk Phrasavath
    Producers: Ellen Kuras and Flora Fernandez-Marengo
    Awards won: Full Frame Spectrum Award
    Filmed over the course of 23 years, this film is a collaboration of cinematographer Ellen Kuras with the film's subject Thavisouk Phrasavath. Victims of the U.S.'s secret war in Laos, Thavisouk's family escaped to a refugee camp and then to America, deposited in a crowded tenement in Brooklyn. The family struggles to survive and stay together, terrorized by local gangs and haunted by memories. A melding of memoir, cinema verité and historical inquiry, The Betrayal is the tale of a country and a family torn asunder, and of the long, painful process of repair.
    In English and Lao with English subtitles
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 1 of 6, 1244 ft. (Reel 67)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 2 of 6, 1348 ft. (Reel 68)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 3 of 6, 1798 ft. (Reel 69)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 4 of 6, 1623 ft. (Reel 70)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 5 of 6, 1390 ft. (Reel 71)
    - 35mm print, So., co., 1.85:1 Flat, Dolby SRD, reel 6 of 6, 1147 ft. (Reel 72)
    - DVD master, TRT 95:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Festival materials, 2008
    - Programs, postcards, flyers, 2008 (Box 6, Box 16)
    - T-shirts, tote bags, 2008; 2 tote bags; 3 t-shirts (Box 16)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2009
  - The Way We Get By (2009)
    Director: Aron Gaudet
    Producer: Gita Pullapilly
    Country: USA
    At the Bangor International Airport in Maine, often the last stop for American troops leaving for war in Iraq and Afghanistan and the first when they return, three senior citizens faithfully greet returning troops or share a moment with departing soldiers. Bill Knight, Joan Gaudet, and Jerry Mundy have spent the last five years welcoming and thanking over 700,000 soldiers. More than a welcome distraction from their own health problems and personal losses, these encounters are a source of strength and inspiration as they face the challenges of growing old.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 5, 1530 ft. (Reel 56)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 5, 1530 ft. (Reel 57)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 5, 1530 ft. (Reel 58)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 5, 1530 ft. (Reel 59)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 5, 1530 ft. (Reel 60)
    - DVD master, TRT 85:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Burma VJ (2008)
    Director: Anders Østergaard
    Producer:
    Awards won: Anne Dellinger Grand Jury Award, the Center for Documentary Studies Filmmaker Award, and the Full Frame/Working Films Award
    TRT: 89:00
    This film tells the story of the Democratic Voice of Burma (DVB), non-profit media organization, and its role in the battle for a free and democratic Myanmar (formerly called Burma). When Buddhist monks began to march against Myanmar's oppressive regime in September 2007, the DVB's brave journalists used small digital camcorders to document the burgeoning demonstrations and subsequent violent repression. The video footage was out of the country for worldwide distribution. Startling on-the-scene footage is combined with evocative reconstructions from the point of view of "Joshua," an exiled member of the DVB team.
    In Burmese and English with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 89:00 (Box 7)
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 89:00 (Box 7)
    - DVD master, TRT 89:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Unmistaken Child (2008)
    Director: Nati Baratz
    Producers: Nati Baratz, Ilil Alexander, and Arik Bernstein
    Country: Israel
    Awards won: Anne Dellinger Grand Jury Award and Full Frame Inspiration Award
    This film follows the four-year search for the reincarnation of Lama Konchog, a world-renowned Tibetan master who passed away in 2001 at age 84. His devoted disciple, Tenzin Zopa sets off on this on this quest through breathtaking landscapes and remote traditional Tibetan villages. Along the way, Tenzin listens to stories about young children with special characteristics and performs rarely seen ritualistic tests to determine the likelihood of reincarnation. He eventually presents the child he believes to be his reincarnated master to the Dalai Lama so that he can make the final decision.
    In English, Tibetan, Hindi and Nepali, with English subtitles.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 61)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 62)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 63)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 64)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 65)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 6 of 6, 1530 ft. (Reel 66)
    - DVD master, TRT 102:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - 12 Notes Down (2008)
    Director: Andreas Koefoed
    Producer: Caroline Blanco
    TRT: 26:00
    Fourteen-year-old Jorgis, the star voice of the Copenhagen Royal Chapel Choir, is faced with a choice. Just weeks before an important concert, his voice has suddenly begun to break. He must choose between damaging his vocal cords trying to hit the high notes or dashing his hopes by walking away. This is a tender portrayal of a universal, yet intensely personal, rite of passage.
    In Danish with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 26:00 (Box 1)
    - Preservation tape master, HDCam, TRT 26:00 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 26:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Voices from El-Sayed (2008)
    Director: Oded Adomi Leshem
    Producers: Itay Ken-Tor, Itay, Liran Atzmor, and Neomi Schori
    TRT: 75:00
    El-Sayed, a Bedouin village in the Negev Desert, is home to the largest community of deaf people in the world, where deafness is seen as a natural part of life. The hearing and the deaf coexist easily in this remote society, but when one father, Salim, decides to get a cochlear implant for his toddler son Muhammad, members of the tight-knit community have distinct, strong opinions. For Muhammad, the road to hearing is long, painful, and garbled. With creative sound editing, Leshem shows how the gift of hearing may feel like a loss of community and identity.
    In Arabic, Hebrew, and local sign language, with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam (PAL), TRT 75:00 (Box 1)
    - DVD master, TRT 75:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Oil Blue (2008)
    Director: Elli Rintala
    Producer: Arttu Nurmi
    This wordless film depicts the scale and beauty of the Baltic Sea. At first, no human presence disturbs the sound, color and force of the Baltic, revealed in a sequence of large, rhythmic shots. Suddenly, all is disrupted by an enormous oil tanker plying the Gulf of Finland. The immense scale of the oil industry mirrors the grandeur of the sea, as humans, technology, and nature converge in unexpected ways in this quiet, lyrical film.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 26:00 (Box 5)
    - DVD master, TRT 25:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Shouting Fire: Stories from the Edge of Free Speech (2008)
    Director: Liz Garbus
    Producers: Liz Garbus, Rory Kennedy, and Jed Rothstein
    TRT: 74:00
    How free is free speech? Filmmaker Liz Garbus interviews her father, well-known First Amendment attorney Martin Garbus about the principle of free speech and its importance to a successful democracy. The film explores several free speech cases, contemporary and historical. Highlighted stories include those of: Ward Churchill, a professor fired from the University of Colorado after 9/11; Debbie Almontaser, the principal of a public school in New York caught up in irrational anti-Muslim frenzy; Tyler Chase Harper, the Poway, California, high school student suspended for wearing a handmade anti-gay T-shirt; and the surveillance of protesters at the 2004 Republican Convention. A wide variety of experts and participants, from across the political spectrum, contribute their thoughts and experiences to this filmic essay.
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 74:00 (Box 5)
    - DVD master, TRT 74:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Love On Delivery (2008)
    Director: Janus Metz
    Producers: Jesper Jack and Henrik Veileborg
    Award won: HBO Emerging Filmmaker Award
    TRT: 59:00
    There are now over five hundred Thai women in Thy, a small Danish fishing community, married to Danish men. Fifteen years ago, there was only Sommai, who has since become a professional matchmaker, bringing family and others over from Thailand to marry Danish men. The film profiles several of the women and follows a new arrival as she the well-worn path from Bangkok to Copenhagen to find a suitable husband in three months before her visa expires, awkwardly courted by a respectable young Dane. Through intimate interviews and beautiful cinematography, director Janus Metz captures a meditation on loneliness and love.
    In Danish, Thai and English with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, TRT 59:00 (Box 5)
    - DVD master, TRT 59:00 (Box 4)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Festival materials, 2009
    - Programs, postcards, 2009 (Box 6, Box 17)
    - Lanyard, tote bags, t-shirts, 2009; 2 bags; 5 shirts (Box 17)
- Full Frame Film Festival, 2010
  - Waste Land (2010)
    Director: Lucy Walker
    Producers: Angus Aynsley and Hank Levine
    Country: United Kingdom and Brazil
    Artist Vik Muniz, known for painting with nontraditional materials, returned to his native Brazil to portray workers in one of the world's largest garbage dumps, Jardim Gramacho, on the outskirts of Rio de Janeiro. He collaborated with these "catadores"-self-designated scavengers of recyclable materials-to create portraits of them made entirely of garbage, returning the profits from their sale to his subjects. Over three years, the filmmakers followed Muniz and this eclectic band of catadores, revealing both the dignity and despair of their lives, in a multivalent collaborative work engaging with issues of artistic process, social justice, responsibility to one's subjects, class mobility, activism, and beauty.
    In English and Portuguese with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, HDCamSR, TRT 95:00 (Box 9)
    - DVD master, TRT 95:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Enemies of the People (2009)
    Director: Rob Lemkin and Thet Sambath
    Producers: Rob Lemkin and Thet Sambath
    Country: United Kingdom and Cambodia
    Awards won: Anne Dellinger Grand Jury Award and Charles E. Guggenheim Emerging Filmmaker Award
    This film is the culmination of ten years of obsessive research by Cambodian investigative reporter Thet Sambath on the reasons for the 1975-1979 Khmer Rouge genocide in which almost two million people, including Thet's parents and brother, were brutally tortured and executed in the killing fields of Cambodia. Thet conducted interviews throughout the countryside, gaining the trust of men who actually carried out the killings. Courageously, they tell the truth and, literally, show where the bodies are buried. But they do not understand why they were ordered to kill. Thet's major achievement is to cultivate the confidence of Pol Pot's second-in-command, Nuon Chea (a.k.a. Brother Number Two); after thirty years of silence, Nuon admits to Thet on camera in detail how they decided to kill party members whom they considered "enemies of the people." A cru+-cial piece in Cambodia's national process of reconciliation, these testimonies trace the transformation of abstract political principles into mass murder.
    In English and Cambodian, with English subtitles.
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 1 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 90)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 2 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 91)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 3 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 92)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 4 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 93)
    - 35mm print, So., co., reel 5 of 5, 1692 ft. (Reel 94)
    - DVD master, TRT 94:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - My Perestroika (2010)
    Director: Robin Hessman
    Producers: Robin Hessman and Rachel Wexler
    Country: United States and United Kingdom
    TRT: 88:00
    What happens when the world you were raised to believe in disappears? Through interviews and expertly edited archival footage and home movies, Hessman explores the experiences of ordinary Russians raised and educated under the Soviet system, who came of age in under glasnost and perestroika. She follows the stories of five Moscow classmates, who reflect honestly on their childhoods and how they reconcile them with their adult lives: history teachers Borya and Lyuba, a married couple; Olga, a single mother who works for a billiard table company; Ruslan, once a popular punk rocker, now a busker in the Moscow metro; and Andrei, a successful businessman who owns a chain of stores selling expensive French shirts.
    In Russian with English subtitles
    - Preservation tape master, HDCamSR, TRT 88:00 (Box 9)
    - DVD master, TRT 88:00 (Box 8)
    - DVD use copy (Box 12)
  - Surviving Hitler: A Love Story (2010)
    Director: John-Keith Wasson
    Producer: John-Keith Wasson
    TRT: 66:00